<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Sam Stoelinga - China</title><link href="https://samos-it.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://samos-it.com/feeds/china.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://samos-it.com/</id><updated>2022-12-06T14:44:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Chinese New Year 2012</title><link href="https://samos-it.com/posts/chinese-new-year-2012.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-01-22T03:24:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-12-06T14:44:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Sam Stoelinga</name></author><id>tag:samos-it.com,2012-01-22:/posts/chinese-new-year-2012.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Chinese New Year aka Spring Festival is the most important festival
in Chinese culture. All the people travel back to their hometown,
because most of them are working/studying in cities far from their own
hometown. That means all train tickets are sold the day they get
available and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Chinese New Year aka Spring Festival is the most important festival
in Chinese culture. All the people travel back to their hometown,
because most of them are working/studying in cities far from their own
hometown. That means all train tickets are sold the day they get
available and plane tickets are super expensive. Luckily Marry was able
to order train tickets via her university, so we didn't have to go
through the hardship of having to buy the tickets ourself. But there was
a little problem with this solution as the tickets will be on somebody's
passport, because I she cant order them on my name because I'm not a
student on her uni.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the 18th we took the train, I was really nervous as I also did not
have my passport and the train ticket not being on my name. My passport
is being hold for extending my visa, and they lately required everybody
to show their passport, else you wouldn't be able to enter the train
station. But everything went fine in the end, the first security check I
just pretended I didn't understand and then they smiled and let me
through. After that they only checked the tickets so it was ok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The train trip itself was pretty decent, could watch outside and there
weren't as many people as I expected. I heard horror stories about not
being able to move at all in the train. It was hard but not impossible, as
people were standing / sitting on the ground because they didn't have a seat.
We were sitting together with students from Marrys uni, so we talked
with them the whole trip, was pretty fun. Time went quite fast and even
managed to sleep for 5 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here in Fuzhou I'm mostly still working so didn't have time to go to
many places yet. Yesterday went to the country side to celebrate new
years with hotpot, a big meal and visited some relatives. The country
side was quite amazing they had small roads and all houses are different
as most of them build the houses them self. Also went to walk around a
little and found a nice castle and river. Will go there again in the
evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My overal impression of Fuzhou is pretty good, I like the atmosphere
and the traffic is much better than Beijing. There are also palm trees and
many tropical trees, which I like.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="China"></category></entry><entry><title>Samwich: Sam's tasty sandwiches</title><link href="https://samos-it.com/posts/samwich-sams-tasty-sandwiches.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-09-12T15:35:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-12-06T14:44:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Sam Stoelinga</name></author><id>tag:samos-it.com,2011-09-12:/posts/samwich-sams-tasty-sandwiches.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I went to sell sandwiches on the streets of Beijing. Why you
think? Just for fun and experience. I often buy food on the streets here
myself, stuff like sushi, pancakes, noodles etc and I really like it.
It's quick fun and tasty. So I also wanted to do that …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I went to sell sandwiches on the streets of Beijing. Why you
think? Just for fun and experience. I often buy food on the streets here
myself, stuff like sushi, pancakes, noodles etc and I really like it.
It's quick fun and tasty. So I also wanted to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link to foto
album: &lt;a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/118136053313378320646/Beijing2011"&gt;https://picasaweb.google.com/118136053313378320646/Beijing2011&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I first went to Weiduomei 味多美 to buy some Baguettes(stokbrood),
that french long crispy bread, we bought 2 for 12元 \~1,20 euro. After
that we went to the supermarket to buy tuna fish(12元 \~1,40 euro) in
can and olive oil and a plate to put the sandwiches on. After coming
back at the appartment I still needed to buy tomatoes and vegetable,
which we bought for 4 yuan \~ 0,40 euro. So in total all the ingredients
costed 30元 \~3 euro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we got all the ingredients around 7 o'clock I started making the
sandwiches with tuna, tomato, salad and olive oil, with tomato ketchup.
At 8 o'clock we started selling, in the beginning I felt weird all the
people had to laugh also at me when they saw a foreigner selling stuff
on the street, many people looked at the paper Lindan wrote:Tuna
sandwich Big ones 10元, small ones 5元. The first 10 minutes many people
looked but nobody buyed, although I was screaming Jing Chang Yu San Ming
zi,  Da de 10 kuai, Xiao de 5 kuai, still people didn't want to buy it.
Some people told me they are full and just ate hehe. But after some time
our first customer bought a small one it were 2 girls. After that it
went pretty quick within 1 hour we sold nearly all and though it is
enough, now we want to eat what's left ourself haha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end we earned 35元, but the costs of all the sandwiches were
30元. We ate 2 sandwiches ourself, so we ate free sandwiches today and
still made 5 yuan and lots of fun. Not bad! Gonna do this again next
time, but then a little bigger.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="China"></category></entry><entry><title>The Beijing Bike Tour and China Belly Problems</title><link href="https://samos-it.com/posts/the-beijing-bike-tour-and-china-belly-problems.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-08-20T14:23:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-12-06T14:44:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Sam Stoelinga</name></author><id>tag:samos-it.com,2011-08-20:/posts/the-beijing-bike-tour-and-china-belly-problems.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;New
pics are added to the same
album: &lt;a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/118136053313378320646/Beijing2011WithBart#"&gt;https://picasaweb.google.com/118136053313378320646/Beijing2011WithBart#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day before yesterday went on bike tour to some famous lakes in
Beijing (Beihai, Houhai, Qianhai, Xihai) and some temple which was
closed already :( We biked the following path I created the route on
Google …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;New
pics are added to the same
album: &lt;a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/118136053313378320646/Beijing2011WithBart#"&gt;https://picasaweb.google.com/118136053313378320646/Beijing2011WithBart#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day before yesterday went on bike tour to some famous lakes in
Beijing (Beihai, Houhai, Qianhai, Xihai) and some temple which was
closed already :( We biked the following path I created the route on
Google Maps for people, who want to try it also: &lt;a href="http://maps.google.com/maps/ms?authuser=0&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;oe=UTF8&amp;amp;msa=0&amp;amp;msid=212889837162657669218.0004aaeb65bce60c1bf49" title="The Route on Google Maps"&gt;The Route on Google
Maps&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="425" height="350" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" src="http://maps.google.com/maps/ms?hl=en&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;oe=UTF8&amp;amp;msa=0&amp;amp;msid=212889837162657669218.0004aaeb65bce60c1bf49&amp;amp;vpsrc=6&amp;amp;ll=39.962912,116.367874&amp;amp;spn=0.0921,0.145912&amp;amp;z=12&amp;amp;output=embed"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View &lt;a href="http://maps.google.com/maps/ms?hl=en&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;oe=UTF8&amp;amp;msa=0&amp;amp;msid=212889837162657669218.0004aaeb65bce60c1bf49&amp;amp;vpsrc=6&amp;amp;ll=39.962912,116.367874&amp;amp;spn=0.0921,0.145912&amp;amp;z=12&amp;amp;source=embed"&gt;Beijing Bike Tour Wudaokou -&amp;gt;
Beihai&lt;/a&gt;
in a larger map&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bike tour itself was also already pretty good, we didn't use the
normal roads but tried to go through the neighborhoods around here. That
was pretty fun, the neighborhood we went through seemed a little poor
many dirt on the street and many people selling vegetables, also saw a
store selling chickens, which were still alive. Actually we were
planning to start at Xihai and go down to Beihai, but because we went
much faster than expected we ended up at Beihai and went up again to
Xihai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After arriving at Beihai we decided to go in and pay the small entrance
fee, which I really hate. Don't wanna pay for some touristic attraction.
It will make me feel too much like a tourist. Inside the park it looked
pretty good, we went with a small boat to the other side of the lake. On
the boat I talked with some Chinese kids and his father was using his
iPad to make pictures and videos. We were also on some of those pics :P&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday we went to the Olympic park, a park which they built just for
relaxing and beauty. At the entrance of the park there is a big lake
with many golden carps, which you can feed and touch if you are quick
enough :P We also fed them some Chinese white bread. After it became
dark, we went fishing nearby the Olympic park, but didn't catch any :(
Last time I went fishing there with Lindan, we catched 2 gold fishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we planned to go to the great wall, but Bart was a little sick
because we traveled too much. Not serious luckily, just little
uncomfortable in the belly. The standard stuff you get in China. But I'm
there no need to worry, already bought some western food like bread and
jam and water. He is already feeling much better. But having a good
relax also wasn't that bad for myself also :P&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow we will even go out to travel again if Bart is totally
recovered. We will go to Summer Palace (Yi he yuan) and another famous
park nearby called Yuan ming yuan.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="China"></category></entry><entry><title>The Watercube and it's big waterpark</title><link href="https://samos-it.com/posts/the-watercube-and-its-big-waterpark.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-08-18T04:53:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-12-06T14:44:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Sam Stoelinga</name></author><id>tag:samos-it.com,2011-08-18:/posts/the-watercube-and-its-big-waterpark.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The day before yesterday we went to a big waterpark inside the Watercube
in the Olympic Park. We watched some pictures and thought it was really
big, but when we came there we noticed it wasn't as big as we thought :P
Pictures not only lie with girls, but also …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The day before yesterday we went to a big waterpark inside the Watercube
in the Olympic Park. We watched some pictures and thought it was really
big, but when we came there we noticed it wasn't as big as we thought :P
Pictures not only lie with girls, but also with waterparks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.samos-it.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/aqualoop.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Aqualoop in Beijing
Waterpark" src="http://blog.samos-it.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/aqualoop.jpg" title="Aqualoop in Beijing Waterpark"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was still pretty good though, there were 3 pretty high, fast and
scary slides and the others were more for kids. There was also the most
crazy slide I ever saw. When we saw it outside we already thought wow
this is really fast and steep. They first shoot you fast down and then
with the speed you gain you will go up again, nearly like a
rollercoaster with a loop inside. But that wasn't all when we went
upstairs to see the entrance of the slide it got even more crazy. There
was a machine which looked like coffin or capsule, which the guy there
will open for you and asks you to go in. Then they close the coffin and
a womans voice says 3-2-1 and the floor under your feet goes away and
you fall down in the slide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So who would want to take such a slide? Well not so many, also nearly no
people toke it so I certainly didn't want to risk my life :P But Bart
really wanted to take it and insisted that he would only take it if I
took it. So I first interviewed a girl who took the slide and asked her
if she felt like she had to puke or got hurt or felt dizzy and such.
After the interview was positive I agreed to go with Bart and risk my
life haha. I was pretty nervous when the woman said 3-2-1 but when I got
out I felt it wasn't that scary. Although I got hurt a little, I have a
small wound on my leg now because it went too fast and my leg got burned
or something I guess. This is the slide in
question: &lt;a href="http://waterpark.water-cube.com/english/Attractions_AquaLoop.aspx"&gt;http://waterpark.water-cube.com/english/Attractions_AquaLoop.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all it was pretty fun, I also never knew there was a waterpark
inside the Watercube. But thanks to Bart and his mother, who actually
knew there was a waterpark, we went there :) Bart treated us, pretty
good :D Today we will go on a bike trip through whole Beijing. Tomorrow
probably more about that :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="China"></category></entry><entry><title>Bart and his lost Bike</title><link href="https://samos-it.com/posts/bart-and-his-lost-bike.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-08-11T15:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-12-06T14:44:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Sam Stoelinga</name></author><id>tag:samos-it.com,2011-08-11:/posts/bart-and-his-lost-bike.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday Bart went on a trip to Tianmen Square, but after coming back I got
a call that his bike got lost. So my first thought was must be stolen,
but then he said he put it in front of the police post. So I gave it
another thought and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday Bart went on a trip to Tianmen Square, but after coming back I got
a call that his bike got lost. So my first thought was must be stolen,
but then he said he put it in front of the police post. So I gave it
another thought and maybe thought it can still be found if we have look.
So Lindan and me went to Wudaokou to check, where we found there are no
bikes so maybe the bike shouldn't be put there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few moments later Lindan found a sign saying in Chinese characters
"You can't put your bike here, you should be responsible for your own
acting(禁止停放自行车，后果自负。" Which Bart couldn't understand of
course. So Lindan first asked some cleaner or traffic guy, where they
would put the bikes, but he didn't know. Then we asked at the police
station and they said the put it at a nearby bike parking place. At the
bike parking place it was just a matter of finding the bike and paying 2
eurocent, which is the normal price for 1 day parking. So it all ended well.
I will also study reading and writing Chinese
characters more, seems it's quite useful here.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="China"></category></entry><entry><title>A New Start in Beijing</title><link href="https://samos-it.com/posts/a-new-start-in-beijing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-08-11T07:07:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-12-06T14:44:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Sam Stoelinga</name></author><id>tag:samos-it.com,2011-08-11:/posts/a-new-start-in-beijing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Pics: &lt;a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/118136053313378320646/Beijing2011WithBart"&gt;https://picasaweb.google.com/118136053313378320646/Beijing2011WithBart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a tough trip, waiting in moscow for 8,5 hours we finally arrived
in Beijing. On the way to the hotel Bart found the traffic here a little rough
and dangerous, but actually I found the driver today was driving quite peacefully …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Pics: &lt;a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/118136053313378320646/Beijing2011WithBart"&gt;https://picasaweb.google.com/118136053313378320646/Beijing2011WithBart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a tough trip, waiting in moscow for 8,5 hours we finally arrived
in Beijing. On the way to the hotel Bart found the traffic here a little rough
and dangerous, but actually I found the driver today was driving quite peacefully already haha.
Guess I got used to the kamikaze drivers, which cross the roads
the way depending on luck whether they live or die. After arriving at
the hotel we were greeted with a friendly NiHao(ni hau).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hjinnswks.becod.com/upfile/200911/24/70519_1259042826KKjE.jpg" title="Hotel"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the hotel we lived in for 168Yuan/night (17 euro). We also
helped Bart to rent a kid's bike for 6 euro for this month. The bike
here is pretty handy. We went to bike for half an hour and arrived at
the mountain.
It was my third time already to go to the mountain. The first time was with
Lindan on the bike and 2nd time I went with my old classmates. It's my
favorite mountain. Here are some
pics: &lt;a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/118136053313378320646/Beijing2011WithBart"&gt;https://picasaweb.google.com/118136053313378320646/Beijing2011WithBart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also went to the olympic park, which you can see on the pics. Also
been there for several times already but I still like it there, always
nice and cosy, people dancing, singing and chilling. Next time we will
go there in the daytime so we can feed the koi carps there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although we did a lot of fun things, we also had to find
an apartment because we will be staying here for 1 year. Yea it's
definite now. We need to pay the rent for 1 year, because the landlord
lives far away and this was how they wanted things done. I first thought
maybe it's a cheater, but we already registered at the police so he isn't
a cheater. But need to get enough money before the end of the month. He
first even said if you dont have enough now we can't rent it out.. So we
arranged we can pay the remaining money at the end of the month. I will
have to work hard this year I think :P The apartment is really good
though, nice living room and good furniture big bed, everything I need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tonight will go to the outside swimming pool again. Lindan's swimming
skills improved a lot, but still needs practice so she won't die when
she falls in the sea. Thanks to Bart's mother we also know we can go to
something much better than Tikibad in the watercube(in Olympic Park). We
are planning to go there somewhere soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="China"></category></entry><entry><title>Sam the terrorist arrived in China</title><link href="https://samos-it.com/posts/sam-the-terrorist-arrived-in-china.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-02-13T00:08:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-12-06T14:44:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Sam Stoelinga</name></author><id>tag:samos-it.com,2011-02-13:/posts/sam-the-terrorist-arrived-in-china.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It has been some days I guess since I have been away from Hollad. But it has been kind of hectic. I will start
from the trip till today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trip started early at 6:30, train to Schiphol and than flight to
London, wait in London for 5 hours …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It has been some days I guess since I have been away from Hollad. But it has been kind of hectic. I will start
from the trip till today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trip started early at 6:30, train to Schiphol and than flight to
London, wait in London for 5 hours. So I was waiting and got little
bored and decided to walk around for a bit and sit at some other places,
and watch some episodes on my laptop. Than when I saw I could check in
for my flight to Beijing I noticed I forgot my jacket somewhere, so I
went to look for it at the places I went before. Because this jacket is
my 4-5 year old favorite jacket :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I found it after 10 minutes of searching and thought ah great just
get it. Than I noticed there were more securtiy than normally around me.
I thought hmm just walk away and at that moment one of them talked to
me, asking me if it was my jacket. What is in your pocket? Why did you
leave your jacket? What is the flashing light in the jacket? (My bike
light, but forgot i took that with me haha)What is your destination?
What is your intention? What will you do in beijing? And he kept
complaining it was really not good to leave something... he asked me
more questions but can't remember all of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a little trouble I arrived in Beijing, took some subway to get to
the hotel and meet Marry again :D was really good. We stayed in a hotel
for 2 days while searching for appartments. Some of the appartments were
so bad haha, with toilets which looked like they weren't cleaned for
weeks, but we finally found one for a decent price. A 2 bedroom
appartement with a living room, and kitchen for 400 euro a month. House
prices are quite high here in Beijing compared to Xiamen. To buy a house
also costs like 200.000 euro or more for 60-80m2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has also been some snow really fun, because it was Marrys first
time to see snow in her whole life. Had some lil snowfights etc hehe :D
Too bad didn't make pictures yet, will try to make more. We got a camera
just forget to take it...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: Made some pics of the appartment, you can see them
here: &lt;a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/sammiestoel/BeijingInternship2011Appartment#"&gt;https://picasaweb.google.com/sammiestoel/BeijingInternship2011Appartment#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="China"></category><category term="china"></category></entry></feed>